<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<device name="onfi_flash" desc="model of generic ONFI NAND flash memory" documentation="The &lt;class&gt;onfi_flash&lt;/class&gt; class is a generic NAND Flash Memory model that is compliant to ONFI 1.0 standard.

The following commands are supported:

Read&lt;br/&gt;Change Read Column&lt;br/&gt;Block Erase&lt;br/&gt;Read Status&lt;br/&gt;Read Status Enhanced&lt;br/&gt;Page Program&lt;br/&gt;Change Write Column&lt;br/&gt;Read ID&lt;br/&gt;Read Parameter Page&lt;br/&gt;Reset

Other commands are currently not supported.

The &lt;b&gt;data_image&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;spare_image&lt;/b&gt; attributes must points to image objects holding the data and spare area data of the flash of size consistent with the parameter of the device.

The following attributes regarding device parameters are required to be properly set before object instantiation (and can not be changed after configuration):

&lt;b&gt;bus_width&lt;/b&gt;: data bus width of this device, either 8 or 16&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;data_bytes_per_page&lt;/b&gt;: value multiple of 512&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;pages_per_block&lt;/b&gt;: value multiple of 2&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;blocks&lt;/b&gt;: total number of blocks&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;id_bytes&lt;/b&gt;: the electronic signature of this device returned by &lt;b&gt;Read ID&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;b&gt;parameter_page&lt;/b&gt;: 256+ bytes of device parameters read by &lt;b&gt;Read Parameter Page&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

The following attribute regarding device parameters are optional, if not set before object instantiation it will be calculated from &lt;b&gt;data_bytes_per_page&lt;/b&gt;:

&lt;b&gt;spare_bytes_per_page&lt;/b&gt;: range from 1 to 2208&lt;br/&gt;The following attributes can be read for information purpose:

&lt;b&gt;total_bytes_per_page&lt;/b&gt;: &lt;b&gt;data_bytes_per_page&lt;/b&gt; + &lt;b&gt;spare_bytes_per_page&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

Further information can be found in the documentation of the individual attributes.

&lt;b&gt;Notes&lt;/b&gt;

Devices with 16-bit bus width will interpret the data in the images as little-endian. For example, if column 0 of page 0 is read, byte 0 in the image will be returned in bit 0 - 7 and byte 1 in bit 8-15. If you use an image in big-endian format you must therefore byte-swap it before loading it.

" bitorder="le">
  <bank name="regs" byte_order="little-endian" function="0">
  </bank>
</device>
